<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tinc on oblivious observer</title>
    <link>https://oblivious.observer/tags/tinc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tinc on oblivious observer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oblivious.observer/tags/tinc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinc different! - Part II: The Two Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://oblivious.observer/posts/tincdifferent-ii-tinc-nixos-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oblivious.observer/posts/tincdifferent-ii-tinc-nixos-module/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of my little series about tinc and NixOS, where I first shortly introduced tinc and then explained how to set it up on Linux in general as well as on NixOS. This part is more or less a rewrite of a question I posted to the NixOS discourse a while ago.
For a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been using tinc on a bunch of infrastructure and so far it&amp;rsquo;s basically been rock solid: once set up nodes anywhere simply join their network and become reachable for anyone who needs to access them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinc different! - Part I: The Fellowship of the Ping</title>
      <link>https://oblivious.observer/posts/tincdifferent-i-tinc-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oblivious.observer/posts/tincdifferent-i-tinc-nixos/</guid>
      <description>This is a post about tinc - a nifty little Mesh VPN service. It is also the first part of a little series of posts related to tinc and NixOS. In this first part I&amp;rsquo;ll just write a bit about how to set up tinc, then in the second part I&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look into how writing a NixOS module can managing tinc networks easier. And finally in the third part I&amp;rsquo;ll present a rewrite of the module with a bunch more features.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>